<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>News on GDAńsk CA Group</title><link>https://houp.github.io/gdaca/news/</link><description>Recent content in News on GDAńsk CA Group</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.147.5</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 10:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://houp.github.io/gdaca/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Research Group Receives Major EU Grant for AI Research</title><link>https://houp.github.io/gdaca/news/2025-05-20-new-research-grant/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://houp.github.io/gdaca/news/2025-05-20-new-research-grant/</guid><description>&lt;p>We are excited to announce that our research group has been awarded a prestigious €2.5 million grant from the European Research Council (ERC) to advance our work in artificial intelligence and machine learning.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-overview">Project Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The three-year project, titled &amp;ldquo;Advanced Neural Architectures for Real-World Applications,&amp;rdquo; will focus on developing novel deep learning methodologies that can be applied to complex real-world problems in healthcare, autonomous systems, and environmental monitoring.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="research-goals">Research Goals&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Develop more efficient neural network architectures&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create robust AI systems for critical applications&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Establish new benchmarks for AI performance evaluation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Foster international collaboration in AI research&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="team-expansion">Team Expansion&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This grant will allow us to expand our team by hiring 3 PhD students and 2 postdoctoral researchers. We will be announcing these positions in the coming weeks.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Team Presents Research at International AI Conference</title><link>https://houp.github.io/gdaca/news/2025-05-15-conference-presentation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 14:30:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://houp.github.io/gdaca/news/2025-05-15-conference-presentation/</guid><description>&lt;p>Our research team successfully presented groundbreaking findings at the International Conference on Artificial Intelligence (ICAI 2025) held in Amsterdam, Netherlands.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="presentation-highlights">Presentation Highlights&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Dr. Witold Bolt delivered a keynote presentation on &amp;ldquo;Scalable Machine Learning Architectures for Edge Computing,&amp;rdquo; which received outstanding feedback from the international research community.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="key-contributions">Key Contributions&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Novel approach to distributed learning on resource-constrained devices&lt;/li>
&lt;li>40% improvement in inference speed compared to existing methods&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Real-world validation in IoT sensor networks&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="conference-impact">Conference Impact&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The presentation attracted significant interest from both academic researchers and industry representatives. We have already received several collaboration proposals and invitations to present at other venues.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Welcome Dr. Barbara Wolnik to Our Research Team</title><link>https://houp.github.io/gdaca/news/2025-05-10-new-team-member/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://houp.github.io/gdaca/news/2025-05-10-new-team-member/</guid><description>&lt;p>We are delighted to welcome Dr. Barbara Wolnik as a new postdoctoral researcher to our team!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="background">Background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Dr. Wolnik joins us from the Technical University of Munich, where she completed her PhD in Computer Science with a focus on distributed systems and cloud computing architectures.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="research-expertise">Research Expertise&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Distributed Computing&lt;/strong>: Specializing in fault-tolerant distributed algorithms&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Cloud Technologies&lt;/strong>: Experience with containerization and microservices&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Performance Optimization&lt;/strong>: Expert in system performance analysis and tuning&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="current-projects">Current Projects&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Dr. Wolnik will be leading our new research initiative on &amp;ldquo;Resilient Distributed Computing for Critical Infrastructure,&amp;rdquo; working closely with our industry partners.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>